<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-08T23:58:29-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//</id><title type="html">Great Lakes Adiban Society</title><subtitle>The Great Lakes Adiban Society is a newly-founded organization intended to provide a regional forum for scholars of Islamicate adab, particularly of the medieval and early modern periods. To join our group, go to https://lists.uchicago.edu/web/info/glas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CfP: Great Lakes Adiban Workshop, Chicago 2018</title><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2018/06/15/wkshop-cfp-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CfP: Great Lakes Adiban Workshop, Chicago 2018" /><published>2018-06-15T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-15T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2018/06/15/wkshop-cfp-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2018/06/15/wkshop-cfp-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatlakesadiban.github.io/&quot;&gt;Great Lakes Adiban Society (GLAS)&lt;/a&gt; invites submissions for its second annual workshop, scheduled to take place at the University of Chicago, October 6–7, 2018. We particularly welcome papers that are works in progress and would benefit from extensive discussion and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Society hopes to provide a regional forum for scholars of Islamicate &lt;em&gt;adab&lt;/em&gt;, particularly of the medieval and early modern periods, to meet and share their work. We leave our parameters intentionally broad in order to invite as wide a collaboration as can be useful, but we are basically engaged with the literatures of the broad complex of premodern Muslim societies from the Danube to the Deccan. This naturally includes the major Islamicate languages of Arabic, Persian, Turkish, and Urdu, as well as others (Armenian, Georgian, Hebrew, Spanish, etc.) that participate in similar literary conventions. We welcome and encourage scholars working in any of these languages to consider participating!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who wish to participate in the workshop should fill out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/VcFedoP3CDibSXNW2&quot;&gt;online application&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;August 15, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;. Please note that each accepted paper will be given 45 minutes for presentation and discussion; because of this, we have limited space on our schedule and may have to turn down some submissions if get too many. In such an event, preference will generally be given to scholars in the Great Lakes region, per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatlakesadiban.github.io/about/&quot;&gt;mission&lt;/a&gt; of this organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graduate students note&lt;/em&gt;: we have some funding to help offset at least part of your travel costs! If you would like to apply for this additional aid, there is a space to do so on the application form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to write Cameron Cross at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kchalipa&lt;/code&gt; [at] &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;umich.edu&lt;/code&gt;. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Great Lakes Adiban Society (GLAS) invites submissions for its second annual workshop, scheduled to take place at the University of Chicago, October 6–7, 2018. We particularly welcome papers that are works in progress and would benefit from extensive discussion and feedback.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kalamazoo 2018</title><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/11/kzoo2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kalamazoo 2018" /><published>2018-05-11T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/11/kzoo2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/11/kzoo2018.html">&lt;p&gt;Today the Great Lakes Adiban hosted two panels at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wmich.edu/medievalcongress/&quot;&gt;2018 International Congress on Medieval Studies&lt;/a&gt;, in Kalamazoo, Michigan. The following papers were presented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;253-jahānsāzi-text-space-and-place-in-medieval-islamicate-literary-worlds-schneider-1345&quot;&gt;253. Jahānsāzi: Text, Space, and Place in Medieval Islamicate Literary Worlds (SCHNEIDER 1345)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “Char-takht” of Husayn Abivardi&lt;/strong&gt;: Theodore Beers, Univ. of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning to Be Sufi, Writing to Make History: Malfuzat in the Chishti Context&lt;/strong&gt;: Manpreet Kaur, Columbia Univ.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distant and Imagined Lands of Fiction&lt;/strong&gt;: N. Ipek Huner-Cora, Univ. of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dangerous Authenticity: What It Means to Be from the Iranian “Otherworld”&lt;/strong&gt;: Samuel Lasman, Univ. of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;310-jinn-dragons-and-divs-supernatural-beings-in-medieval-islamicate-literatures-schneider-1345&quot;&gt;310. Jinn, Dragons, and Divs: Supernatural Beings in Medieval Islamicate Literatures (SCHNEIDER 1345)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Monstrous in Medieval Arab versus Medieval Western Writings&lt;/strong&gt;: Sally Abed, Alexandria Univ.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repenting of Poetry: Al-Farazdaq’s Notice to the Devil&lt;/strong&gt;: Kevin Blankinship, Univ. of Utah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devil the Divine: The Sainthood of Iblis in Persian Mysticism and Its Portrayal in Medieval Perso-Islamic Paintings&lt;/strong&gt;: Abolfazl Moshiri, Univ. of Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon-Spawn, Elephant-Men, and the Quiddity of Evil in Persian Epic&lt;/strong&gt;: Cameron Cross, Univ. of Michigan–Ann Arbor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the two panels, we met to discuss our upcoming projects: the GLAS workshop to be held in September 2018, and potential themes for our ICMS 2019 panels. We’ll be posting further details and calls for papers for these two events in the upcoming month or so. Thanks and congrats to all for a great time at Kalamazoo!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today the Great Lakes Adiban hosted two panels at the 2018 International Congress on Medieval Studies, in Kalamazoo, Michigan. The following papers were presented:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GLAS at MEHAT</title><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/05/glas-at-mehat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GLAS at MEHAT" /><published>2018-05-05T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/05/glas-at-mehat</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/05/05/glas-at-mehat.html">&lt;p&gt;The Great Lakes Adiban Society are pleased to be part of the annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://voices.uchicago.edu/mehat/&quot;&gt;Middle East History and Theory Conference&lt;/a&gt;, which was held at the University of Chicago, May 5–6 2018. Our members organized and submitted a panel entitled &lt;em&gt;Men in Love: Masculinity and Madness in Pre-Modern Romances&lt;/em&gt;, featuring the following papers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allison Kanner (University of Chicago), “A Pact Between Conflicting Codes: Javānmardī in Niẓāmī’s Laylī o Majnūn.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexandra Hoffmann (University of Chicago), “Manly King or Mad Lover? On the Meaning of Blackness in Fayżī’s Nal o Daman.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cameron Cross (University of Michigan), “A Dying Man in a Deathless Body: The (Hor)cruxes of Kingship.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Great Lakes Adiban Society are pleased to be part of the annual Middle East History and Theory Conference, which was held at the University of Chicago, May 5–6 2018. Our members organized and submitted a panel entitled Men in Love: Masculinity and Madness in Pre-Modern Romances, featuring the following papers:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ICMS 2018 Panels</title><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/04/15/icms-2018-panels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICMS 2018 Panels" /><published>2018-04-15T22:02:19-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T22:02:19-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/04/15/icms-2018-panels</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//conference/2018/04/15/icms-2018-panels.html">&lt;p&gt;GLAS is the sponsor of two panels in the 53rd International Congress on Medieval Studies, to take place on the campus of Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, MI on May 10–13, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jinn-dragons-and-divs-supernatural-beings-in-medieval-islamicate-literatures&quot;&gt;Jinn, Dragons, and Divs: Supernatural Beings in Medieval Islamicate Literatures&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This panel will address medieval Islamicate literary approaches to creatures who are neither ordinary humans nor ordinary animals. A plethora of spirits, monsters, and other enchanted beings play key roles in Persian, Arabic, and Turkish texts ranging from cosmological, geographical, and medical treatises to works of history, romance, and lyric poetry. How did the intellectual and cultural heritage of Islamic societies, including elements such as Hellenistic learning, pre-Islamic mythology and folklore, and Judaeo-Christian demonology, create a unique environment for writers to explore non-human ontologies? At the same time, authors could employ the explicit invocations of jinn, ghouls, and magic serpents in the Qur’an and hadith as defenses against charges of indulging in mere fantasy. In what ways did these references serve as intellectual justifications for literary curiosity regarding the extreme cases of created life—the invisible, magical, or extraordinary inhabitants of sites both local and exotic? How did situating these entities in either a distant haunted past and a perceptible present shape writers’ relationships to temporality? Open to contributions from scholars of literature, history, religion, and culture, amongst other disciplines, this panel seeks to provide a space for the discussion of these and related questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jahān-sāzī-text-space-and-place-in-medieval-islamicate-literary-worlds&quot;&gt;Jahān-sāzī: Text, Space, and Place in Medieval Islamicate Literary Worlds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This panel will consider the relation of physical environments, real or imagined, to literary production and historiography. As Islam spread to encompass a vast variety of climates and landscapes, both the cultures that it brought in its wake and the indigenous cultures it encountered worked to negotiate the relationships between humans and their environment through literary productions. In later centuries, shifting borders brought narratives of loss, nostalgia, and destruction into play. In literary terms, what did it mean to gain, lose, create or destroy places? How did the lived or perceived conditions of cities, provinces, and wildernesses — both distant and familiar — affect the depiction of those places in literature, or the invention of new places in speculative or fantastical works? How did the spaces through which writers traveled or migrated shape their creations? What role did wider environmental shifts, such as urbanization and climate change, play in the development of literary traditions? By considering perspectives from fields as broad as literary studies, cultural history, geography, and historical ecology, this panel aims to create an interdisciplinary conversation on the building of medieval Islamicate literary worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">GLAS is the sponsor of two panels in the 53rd International Congress on Medieval Studies, to take place on the campus of Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, MI on May 10–13, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GLAS Workshop 2017</title><link href="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2017/09/30/glas-workshop-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GLAS Workshop 2017" /><published>2017-09-30T22:02:19-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-30T22:02:19-04:00</updated><id>https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2017/09/30/glas-workshop-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://greatlakesadiban.github.io//workshop/2017/09/30/glas-workshop-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;/em&gt;: Sat. 9/30 to Sun. 10/1&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Location&lt;/em&gt;: Trimpe Building, Western Michigan  University / Kalamazoo, MI, 49008&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parking is free in front of the building (Lot 39), in Lot 100, and across the street in front of Parking Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;program-schedule&quot;&gt;Program Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saturday-sep-30&quot;&gt;Saturday (Sep 30)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:00–10:45 - Ameena Yovan (U of Michigan): The early maqatil and their authors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:45–11:30 - Ipek Huner (U of Chicago): Visibility and wiles in the marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:30–11:45 - Coffee break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:45–12:30 - Hadi Jorati (Ohio State U): The obscure legacies of Khayyamian poetry and mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:30–2:00 - Lunch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:00–2:45 - Shahla Farghadani (U of Michigan): A matter of taste: Arzu’s innovation in Persian literary criticism and stylistics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:45–3:30 - Shaahin Pishbin (U of Chicago): Expanding horizons and narrowing foci in the 17th-century Persian tazkira&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3:30–3:45 - Coffee break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3:45–4:30 - Allison Kanner (U of Chicago): Disrupting the narrative: A designated room in Nizami’s &lt;em&gt;Haft Paykar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4:30–5:15 - Alexandra Hoffmann (U of Chicago): ‘Nal, why is your body black?’: Finding meaning in Nal’s transformation in Fayzi’s Nal o Daman
6:30 - Dinner at Martini’s Pizza (832 S Westnedge Ave)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-oct-1&quot;&gt;Sunday (Oct 1)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:00–10:45 - Sam Lasman (U of Chicago): Narrating future history: Ayadgar-i Jamaspigand Armes Prydein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:45–11:30 - Marian Smith (U of Michigan): The dispersed corpus of ‘Abdallah Hatifi’s Timurnama: Observations from the field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:30–12:15 - Discussion of the Adiban project, with remarks by Franklin Lewis (U of Chicago), Nathan Tabor (Western Michigan U), and Cameron Cross (U of Michigan)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:15–2:00 - Lunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event was supported through WMU’s Department of Education-funded Undergraduate International Studies and Foreign Language Grant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Date: Sat. 9/30 to Sun. 10/1 Location: Trimpe Building, Western Michigan University / Kalamazoo, MI, 49008</summary></entry></feed>